Finding Aid for the Recordings of Evenings for New Music, 1964-1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Recordings of Evenings for New Music, 1964-1980
Mus. Arc. 31
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Dept.
12 linear feet (162 reel to reel tapes, 278 audio compact discs, 96 DVDs)
There are two sets of 139 CDs: one is labeled Service Copy, the other is labeled In-house Master. They contain audio files at 44.1kHz/16bit resolution. The 96 DVDs are labeled Preservation Master and contain WAV files at 96kHZ/24bit resolution. They are embedded with broadcast wave metadata.
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains recordings of 93 of the approximately 173 concerts presented at the Evenings for New Music concerts from 1964-1980. Approximately 464 works were recorded as well as some spoken introductions to works by their respective composers. The original recordings were made on reel-to-reel tapes. The contents were transferred to cassettes in the 1980s and then digitally reformatted in 2007 onto CDs (service and in-house masters) and DVDs (preservation masters).
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of State University of New York at Buffalo Music Dept.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Historical Note
The Evenings for New Music concert series was a product of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts, established to give young professional performers and composers the opportunity to focus on the production of new music. Lukas Foss, Music Director for the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra 1963-1971, approached Gordon Smith, director of the Albright-Knox Art Gallery 1955-1973, to develop ideas for a Center of New Music in Buffalo. In discussions with Allan Sapp, Director of the University at Buffalo Music Department, and the Rockefeller Foundation, a proposal was submitted to the Foundation for the development of the Center. Modeled after the Evenings-on-the-Roof concert series in Los Angeles, the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts was “founded on notions of providing performing ensembles, of making definitive renditions of new and complicated music feasible, of bringing composers and performers into the closest working relationships, of developing a corpus of recordings and privately-held scores, of establishing a central locus for the study of new techniques of composition notation and performance practice.” The proposal was accepted and the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts began operation in 1964.
Directors of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts included the founders, Lukas Foss and Allan Sapp, who acted as Co-Directors from 1964-68; Lejaren Hiller, Co-Director with Lukas Foss from 1968-74; Jan Williams, Co-Director with Renée Levine from 1974-76; Renée Levine, Center Coordinator from 1964-74 and Co-Director from 1974-78; and Morton Feldman, Music Director from 1976-1980. Performers and composers selected to be fellows at the Center were given the title of Creative Associate.
There were two main concert series produced by the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts: Evenings for New Music concerts and Creative Associate Recitals. Evenings for New Music concerts were performed in Buffalo and also performed, often with changes in programs, at various venues in New York City, including Carnegie Hall, Cooper Union, and the WBAI Radio Free Music Store, at other State University of New York campuses, and at venues in other states, including New Jersey, New Hampshire, Michigan, Indiana, Vermont, and Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains recordings of approximately 464 works performed at 93 of the Evenings for New Music concerts 1964-1980. This finding aid contains a description of the recordings of concerts held by the Music Library. Not all concerts were recorded so the inventory in this finding aid does not represent a complete description of all the concerts presented in the series. A fuller listing can be seen in the online version of the original catalog compiled of the concert programs.
There are more than 200 composers represented in the collection. They include most of the major composers of the first half of the twentieth century, including Cage, Boulez, Babbitt, Schoenberg, Berg, Webern, Stockhausen, Stravinsky, Copland, and Feldman. The composers were often present at the concerts and rehearsals of their works so many of the performances were conducted under the supervision of the composer. The list of composers who appeared as performers in the concerts is equally impressive, including Earle Brown, Bussotti, Cage, Crumb, Del Tredici, Foss, Hiller, Pousseur, Riley, Rzewski, Sahl, and Wuorinen. The performers included some of the most prominent specialists in contemporary music, including Eberhard Blum, Ursula Oppens, Paul Zukofsky, Julius Eastman, Jan Williams, David Tudor, Stuart Dempster, Robert Dick, and Joan La Barbara.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
I. Service copy compact discs reformatted from reel to reel tapes
II. Reel to reel tapes not reformatted
Container List
- Service copy compact discs reformatted from reel to reel tapes, 1964-1980, I.; CD 1-139
  Description of compact discs provided for access with notes about the original tape sources and location of the preservation copy. The In-house master compact discs are numbered in the same sequence, 1-139. Note that in some cases reel to reel tapes were not available at the time reformatting was performed so the Music Library's cassette copies were used as source material instead.
  Chiefly arranged in chronological order of concerts.
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 1, November 29, 1964, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Cassette Side 1-Cassette Side 8 Preservation copy on DVD 1 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 1-2)
    Work number: ENM001-01
    Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965
    Twenty-six simultaneous mosaics for five players (1963)
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jan Williams, percussion; Fredric Myrow, piano; Charles Joseph, violin; Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 4:52
    Work number: ENM001-02
    Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001
    Morisma-Amorisma (1959)
    Performers: Paul Zukofsky, violin; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Buell Neidlinger, bass; George Crumb, piano
    Duration: 10:25
    Work number: ENM001-03
    Mayuzumi, Toshiro, 1929-1997
    Prelude for string quartet (1964)
    Performers: Charles Joseph, Paul Zukofsky, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 9:10
    Work number: ENM001-04
    Crumb, George
    Night music I (1963)
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; John Bergamo, Jan Williams, percussion; Fredric Myrow, George Crumb, pianos
    Duration: 19:14
    Work number: ENM001-05
    Arrigo, Girolamo
    Quatro episodi for soprano and flutes (1963)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute
    Duration: 4:40
    Work number: ENM001-06
    Kotonski, Wlodzimierz
    Trio for flute, guitar, and percussion (1960)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Stanley Silverman, guitar; John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 7:28
    Work number: ENM001-07
    Ellis, Don
    Improvisation (1964)
    Performers: Don Ellis, trumpet; ensemble
    Duration: 7:50
    Work number: ENM001-08
    Brown, Earle, 1926-2002
    Novara (1962)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Don Ellis, trumpet; Fredric Myrow, piano; Paul Zukofsky, Charles Joseph, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 3, January 10, 1965, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Cassette Side 9-Cassette side 17 Preservation copy on DVD 2 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 3)
    Work number: ENM003-01
    Ives, Charles, 1874-1954
    Requiem (1911)
    Performers: Laurence Bogue, baritone; Don Ellis, trumpet, Fredric Myrow, piano
    Duration: 1:27
    Work number: ENM003-02
    Aeschylus and Sophocles (1922)
    Performers: Laurence Bogue, baritone; Fredric Myrow, piano
    Duration: 2:16
    Work number: ENM003-03
    The innate (1916)
    Performers: Laurence Bogue, baritone; Fredric Myrow, piano; Charles Joseph, Paul Zukofsky, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 4:11
    Work number: ENM003-04
    Carter, Elliott, 1908-
    Tell me where is fancy bred (1939)
    Performers: Laurence Bogue, baritone; Stanley Silverman, guitar
    Duration: 2:40
    Work number: ENM003-05
    Myrow, Fredric, 1939-
    Songs from the Japanese (1963-64)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jan Williams, percussion; Fredric Myrow, George Crumb, pianos; Paul Zukofsky, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello, Buell Neidlinger, bass
    Duration: 13:00
    Work number: ENM003-06
    Wolff, Christian, 1934-
    In between places (1963)
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Stanley Silverman, guitar; Paul Zukofsky, violin
    Duration: 4:25
    Work number: ENM003-07
    Young, La Monte
    The four dreams of China (1962). Excerpt The second dream of the high-tension line stepdown transformer.
    Performers: Charles Joseph, Paul Zukofsky, violins; Lukas Foss, reciter
    Duration: 10:45
    Work number: ENM003-08
    Composition no. 6 (1960)
    Performers: Ensemble
    Work number: ENM003-09
    Bussotti, Sylvano
    Sette fogli (1959). Excerpt No. 6. Manifesto per Kalinowski.
    Performers: Ensemble; Sylvano Bussotti, conductor
    Duration: 2:50
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 5, March 4, 1965, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 1-Reel 2, Cassette Side 22 Preservation copy on DVD 3 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 4-5)
    Work number: ENM005-01
    Babbitt, Milton, 1916-
    Two sonnets (1955)
    Performers: Laurence Bogue, baritone; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 8:35
    Work number: ENM005-02
    Sapp, Allen, 1922-1999
    The lady and the lute (1952)
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; George Crumb, harpsichord
    Duration: 17:17
    Work number: ENM005-03
    Silverman, Stanley
    Planh (1965)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jan Williams, percussion; Stanley Silverman, guitar; Charles Joseph, Paul Zukofsky, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 6:20
    Work number: ENM005-04
    Ligeti, György, 1923-2006
    Poème symphonique (1962)
    Performers: Ensemble; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 13:25
    Work number: ENM005-05
    Cage, John
    Theatre piece (1960)
    Duration: 18:50
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 6, March 5, 1965, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 3-Reel 4, Cassette Side 25 Preservation copy on DVD 4 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 6-7)
    Work number: ENM006-01
    Foss, Lukas, 1922-
    Echoi (1963)
    Performers: Richard Dufallo, clarinet; John Bergamo, percussion; Lukas Foss, piano; Howard Colf, violoncello
    Duration: 29:00
    Work number: ENM006-02
    Berio, Luciano, 1925-2003
    Visage (1960)
    Performers: Prerecorded tape; Romano Amidei, mime; Sylvano Bussotti, staging
    Duration: 20:36
    Work number: ENM006-03
    La passion selon Sade (1965)
    Duration: 34:00
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 7, March 6, 1965, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 5-Reel 7 Preservation copy on DVD 5 Performed at Buffalo and Erie County Public Library (Box 1, Cd 8-9)
    Work number: ENM007-01
    Sequenza (1958)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute
    Duration: 7:38
    Work number: ENM007-02
    Pieces de chair II (1959). Excerpt. Five piano pieces for David Tudor
    Performers: David Tudor, piano
    Duration: 20:20
    Work number: ENM007-03
    Kagel, Mauricio
    Sur scene (1959/60)
    Performers: John Horton, actor; James Mitchell, mime; Laurence Bogue, singer; Michael Shaw, Fredric Myrow, George Crumb, keyboards and percussion; Mauricio Kagel, stage direction; David Zierk, lighting design
    Duration: unknown
    Note: United States premiere
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 9, April 25, 1965, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 8-Reel 10 Preservation copy on DVD 6 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 10-11)
    Work number: ENM009-01
    Fuller, Ramon
    Music for two channel tape and two percussionists (1964)
    Performers: John Bergamo, Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 7:13
    Work number: ENM009-02
    Duration: 8:33
    Work number: ENM009-03
    Sahl, Michael, 1934-
    Fivepiece (1962)
    Performers: John Bergamo, Jan Williams, percussion; Michael Sahl, piano; Stanley Silverman, guitar; Buell Neidlinger, bass
    Duration: 11:42
    Work number: ENM009-04
    Salzman, Eric
    In praise of the owl and the cuckoo (1963)
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Laurence Trott, flute; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Stanley Silverman, guitar; Paul Zukofsky, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola
    Duration: 13:05
    Work number: ENM009-05
    Pousseur, Henri
    Madrigal III (1962)
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; John Bergamo, Jan Williams, percussion; Michael Sahl, piano; Charles Joseph, violin; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 6:35
    Work number: ENM009-06
    Hamilton, Iain, 1922-2000
    Dialogues (1965)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Laurence Trott, flute; Don Ellis, trumpet; John Bergamo, percussion; Michael Sahl, piano; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 15:04
    Work number: ENM009-07
    Wernick, Richard, 1934-
    Stretti (1965)
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Stanley Silverman, guitar; Paul Zukofsky, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola
    Duration: 14:04
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 11, May 9, 1965, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 11-Reel 13 Preservation copy on DVD 7 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 12)
    Work number: ENM011-01
    Shapero, Harold, 1920-
    Trio for violin, viola and cello (1938)
    Performers: Paul Zukofsky, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 11:28
    Work number: ENM011-02
    Six pieces for kettledrums (1950). Excerpts V. Recitative. II. Moto perpetuo. I. Improvisation.
    Performers: Jan Williams, timpani
    Duration: 11:17
    Work number: ENM011-03
    Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974
    Suite for violin, clarinet and piano (1937)
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Paul Zukofsky, violin; Michael Sahl, piano
    Duration: 12:23
    Work number: ENM011-04
    Riegger, Wallingford, 1885-1961
    Sonatine for violin and piano (1947)
    Performers: Charles Joseph, violin; Carlo Pinto, piano
    Duration: 7:11
    Work number: ENM011-05
    Time cycle (1961)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jan Williams, percussion; Fredric Myrow, piano; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 21:04
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 12, May 10, 1965, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 14-Reel 15 Preservation copy on DVD 8 Performed at Howard University, Cramton Auditorium (Box 1, Cd 13)
    Work number: ENM012-01
    Orbon, Julian, 1925-1991
    Partita for keyboard instrument, string quartet, and harpsichord concertante (1964)
    Performers: Michael Sahl, harmonium; George Crumb, celesta; Jan Williams, vibraphone; Charles Joseph, Paul Zukofsky, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Robert Parris, harpsichord
    Work number: ENM012-03
    Mimetics (Metapiece) for piano (1961), performed with Sonant, for Spanish guitar and electric guitar, double bass and membranophones (1960?), and Metapiece (Mimetics) for piano solo (1961)
    Performers: Fredric Myrow, piano; Stanley Silverman, guitar; Buell Neidlinger, doublebass; John Bergamo, Jan Williams, percussion; Mauricio Kagel, piano via electronic tape on Metapiece
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 13, November 7, 1965, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 16-Reel 18 Preservation copy on DVD 9 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 14)
    Work number: ENM013-01
    Globokar, Vinko, 1934-
    Plan (1965)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Andrew White III, oboe; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Vinko Globokar, trombone; John Bergamo, reciter/percussion
    Duration: 4:20
    Work number: ENM013-02
    Six pieces for kettledrums (1950). Excerpts III. Saeta. IV. March. VI. Canary.
    Duration: 11:30
    Work number: ENM013-03
    Nilsson, Bo
    Zwanzig Gruppen (1957-58)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Andrew White III, oboe; Sherman Friedland, clarinet
    Duration: 5:35
    Work number: ENM013-04
    Biel, Michael von
    Quartet, strings, no. 1 (1963)
    Performers: Dagmar von Biel, Charles Joseph, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Michael von Biel, violoncello
    Duration: 6:14
    Work number: ENM013-05
    Quartet with accompaniment (1965)
    Performers: Dagmar von Biel, Charles Joseph, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Michael von Biel, Jay Humeston, violoncellos; Buell Neidlinger, bass
    Duration: 10:22
    Work number: ENM013-06
    Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951
    Pierrot Lunaire, op. 21 (1912)
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Karl Kraber, flute; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Charles Joseph, violin; Jean Dupouy viola; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 36:08
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 15, December 18, 1965, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 19-Reel 22 Preservation copy on DVD 10 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 15)
    Work number: ENM015-01
    Taylor, Cecil, 1929-
    Toll (1962)
    Performers: Andrew White III, alto saxophone; John Bergamo, percussion; Buell Neidlinger, bass
    Duration: 17:06
    Work number: ENM015-02
    Sequenza II for solo harp (1963)
    Performers: Francis Pierre, harp
    Duration: 6:40
    Work number: ENM015-03
    Porena, Boris
    Four canonical lieder (1958)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Sherman Friedland, clarinet
    Duration: 5:55
    Work number: ENM015-04
    Herzgewächse, op. 20 (1911)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Andrew White III, oboe; David Tudor, harmonium; Francis Pierre, harp; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 2:58
    Work number: ENM015-05
    Simons, Netty
    Facets 3 (1962)
    Performers: Andrew White III, oboe; Fredric Myrow, piano
    Duration: 7:08
    Work number: ENM015-06
    Book for three (1961)
    Performers: David Tudor, Michael von Biel, amplified, prepared barbecue broilers
    Duration: 23:45
    Work number: ENM015-07
    Amy, Gilbert
    Inventions (1961)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; Jan Williams, percussion; David Tudor, piano; Pierre Francis, harp
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 17, February 19, 1966, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 23-Reel 25 Preservation copy on DVD 11 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 16)
    Work number: ENM017-01
    Puig, Michel, 1930-
    Dedicase I and II (1964-65)
    Performers: Vinko Globokar, trombone
    Duration: 3:00
    Work number: ENM017-02
    Austin, Larry
    Changes (1965)
    Duration: 9:00
    Work number: ENM017-03
    Bergamo, John
    Tanka (1964)
    Performers: John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 12:00
    Work number: ENM017-04
    Reck, David Benedict, 1935-
    Night sounds and dream (1965)
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; John Bergamo, percussion; Buell Neidlinger, bass
    Duration: 13:30
    Work number: ENM017-05
    All the way around and back (before 1908)
    Performers: Fredric Myrow, piano; Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Jan Williams, bells; Pamela Gearhart, violin; unidentified trumpet player
    Work number: ENM017-06
    In re con moto et al (1908)
    Performers: Pamela Gearhart, Charles Joseph, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Helene Triantafillou, violoncello; Fredric Myrow, piano
    Duration: 6:30
    Work number: ENM017-07
    Ensemble '65 (1965)
    Performers: Karl Kraber, flute; David Pinkow, horn; Vinko Globokar, trombone; Jan Williams, John Bergamo, percussion; Michael Sahl, Fredric Myrow, pianos; Charles Joseph, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola; Helene Triantafillou, violoncello; Buell Neidlinger, bass
    Duration: 18:15
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 19, March 20, 1966, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 26-Reel 29 Preservation copy on DVD 12 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 17-18)
    Work number: ENM019-01
    Webern, Anton von, 1883-1945
    Quartet, piano-viola-clarinet-saxophone op. 22 (1930)
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Andrew White III, tenor saxophone; Charles Joseph, violin; Fredric Myrow, piano
    Duration: 5:30
    Work number: ENM019-02
    Miroir de Votre Fauste (1964). Excerpt Le Tarot d'Henri (s)
    Performers: Frederic Rzewski, piano
    Duration: 13:27
    Work number: ENM019-03
    Trois chants sacrés (1951)
    Performers: Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, soprano; Charles Joseph, violin; Jean Dupouy, Jay Humeston, violoncello; Henri Pousseur, conductor
    Duration: 4:39
    Work number: ENM019-04
    Rzewski, Frederic
    Composition for 2 performers (1964)
    Performers: Frederic Rzewski, David Tudor, pianos
    Duration: 16:42
    Work number: ENM019-05
    Ichiyanagi, Toshi, 1933-
    Duet for piano and stringed instrument (1961)
    Performers: Jean Dupouy, viola; David Tudor, piano
    Duration: 15:05
    Work number: ENM019-06
    Sapporo (1962)
    Performers: Vinko Globokar, trombone; Michael Sahl, David Tudor, pianos; Dagmar von Biel, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola; Michael von Biel, violoncello; Henri Pousseur, conductor
    Duration: 30:41
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 21, April 24, 1966, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 30-Reel 32 Preservation copy on DVD 13 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 19)
    Work number: ENM021-01
    Vibone (1963)
    Performers: Vinko Globokar, trombone; John Bergamo, percussion
    Duration: 5:34
    Work number: ENM021-02
    Satie, Erik, 1866-1925
    La piège de Méduse (1921)
    Performers: Sherman Friedland, clarinet; Richard Jones, trumpet; Vinko Globokar, trombone; Jan Williams, John Bergamo, percussion; Charles Joseph, violin; Jay Humeston, violoncello; Buell Neidlinger, bass; Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, Carol Plantamura, actresses; Laurence Bogue, Jean Dupouy, actors; Albert Reid, dancer; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 20:14
    Work number: ENM021-03
    Répons (1960/65)
    Performers: Jean Dupouy, narrator; Karl Kraber, flute; Jan Williams, percussion; David Tudor, Michael Sahl, pianos; Marjorie Hartzell, harp; Charles Joseph, violin; Jay Humeston, violoncello
    Duration: 35:08
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 23, November 6, 1966, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 33 Preservation copy on DVD 14 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 20)
    Work number: ENM023-01
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
    Three songs from William Shakespeare (1953)
    Performers: Anne Graff, alto; Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Paul Zonn, clarinet; Jean Dupouy, viola
    Duration: 6:57
    Work number: ENM023-02
    Davidovsky, Mario, 1934-
    Synchronisms No. I for flute and electronic sounds (1963)
    Performers: Shaul Ben Meir, flute
    Duration: 3:43
    Work number: ENM023-03
    Synchronisms No. III for cello and electronic sounds (1964-65)
    Performers: Robert Martin, violoncello
    Work number: ENM023-04
    Synchronisms No. II for flute, clarinet, viola, cello, and electronic sounds (1964)